<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title></title>
 <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/"/>
 <updated>2014-07-23T07:58:38-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.aba-icc.org</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>International Criminal Justice: Mass Atrocities, the International Criminal Court, and the Role of States</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/2014/04/10/aba-icc-project-ad-jones-day-law-firm/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/2014/04/10/aba-icc-project-ad-jones-day-law-firm</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On April 10, 2014, the ABA-ICC Project, the Aspen Institute of Justice and Society Program, the Coalition for the International Criminal Court (CICC), and the Embassy of the Kingdom of the Netherlands co-sponsored two panel programs in Washington, DC at an event entitled “International Criminal Justice: Mass Atrocities, the International Criminal Court, and the Role of States,” that was hosted by the Jones Day law firm at their beautiful offices overlooking the US Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object id=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;flashVars&quot; value=&quot;videoId=3524487487001&amp;amp;playerID=2307908497001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAABsp7SiCE~,aEBLYbQyvvBa8yEVvdO_c5cphEka3MCJ&amp;amp;domain=embed&amp;amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;base&quot; value=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;seamlesstabbing&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;swLiveConnect&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowScriptAccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isVid=1&quot; bgcolor=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; flashvars=&quot;videoId=3524487487001&amp;amp;playerID=2307908497001&amp;amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAABsp7SiCE~,aEBLYbQyvvBa8yEVvdO_c5cphEka3MCJ&amp;amp;domain=embed&amp;amp;dynamicStreaming=true&quot; base=&quot;http://admin.brightcove.com&quot; name=&quot;flashObj&quot; width=&quot;410&quot; height=&quot;353&quot; seamlesstabbing=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; swliveconnect=&quot;true&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; pluginspage=&quot;http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first panel program was devoted to the US role in international criminal justice.  The distinguished panelists were the Hon. Patricia Wald, former judge of the US Court of Appeals - DC Circuit and of the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY), and Stephen Rapp, US Ambassador for Global Criminal Justice. The program was moderated by Stephen Lamony of the Coalition for the International Criminal Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second panel program focused on the successes and challenges at the ICC, and the distinguished panelists were Fatou Bensouda, Prosecutor of the ICC, and Justice Richard Goldstone, former Prosecutor of both the ICTY and ICTR.  The program was moderated by former ABA President Michael S. Greco, Chair of the ABA-ICC Project and its Board of Advisors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the panel discussion some of the issues addressed by Prosecutor Bensouda were the politicization of the ICC, the lack of adequate resources for the ICC, and the misconceptions of the Court’s operations which are undermining the ICC and its important casework:  “Misconceptions are another challenge that the court is facing. I think one of the biggest enemies of the court - if I may put it that way - are the misconceptions or misperceptions of deliberately making sure that the Court is not understood. We need cooperation from states to make sure that the limitations of the court are understood.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One subject addressed by Justice Goldstone was the evolution of the US-ICC relationship:  “I can’t exaggerate the importance that the US has played in the field of international criminal justice. I would go so far as to say that without the United States, we would not have a field of international criminal justice at all.”  The video of the highly informative full program may be viewed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Misconceptions are another challenge that the court is facing. I think one of the biggest enemies of the court - if I may put it that way - are the misconceptions or misperceptions or deliberately making sure that the Court is not understood. We need cooperation from states to make sure that the limitations of the court are understood.” - Fatou Bensouda, ICC Prosecutor  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I can’t exaggerate the importance that the US has played in the field of international criminal justice. I would go so far as to say that without the United States, we would not have a field of international criminal justice at all.”  - Justice Goldstone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Debate: The International Criminal Court in Africa</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/25/debate-the-international-criminal-court-in-africa/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/25/debate-the-international-criminal-court-in-africa</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 25, 2014, American University’s Council on Africa Studies hosted a panel debate on Africa and the ICC with a special focus on recent ICC cases against senior Kenyan governmental officials. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://carllevan.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/ICC-photo-of-all-panelists-2-25-2014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;  The debaters were Prof. David Bosco,f American University and author of “Rough Justice”; Stephen Lamony, senior advisor to the Coalition for the ICC; and Regina Njogu, private Kenya attorney with experience in human rights issues.The moderator of this debate was Michael Greco, former ABA President and chair of the ABA-ICC Project, who began by explaining the ABA’s long-standing support of  the ICC, stating, “The ABA has long been a strong supporter of international criminal justice. Going back to the 1970’s the first policy adopted by the ABA regarding international criminal justice was to endorse the idea of a permanent tribunal for international justice.” Mrs. Njogu’s statements were critical of the ICC, alleging ICC incompetence in bringing justice to Africa, specifically in the case of Kenya. However, these allegations were firmly rejected by the other panelists who provided evidence to the contrary. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/XyYs7NzCsO8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The ABA has long been a strong supporter of international criminal justice. Going back to the 1970’s, the first policy adopted by the ABA regarding international criminal justice was to endorse the idea of a permanent tribunal for international justice.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Michael Greco                                                                                                                        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What needs to be understood is, unlike national jurisdictions which have power of the police to do these things, the ICC works on cooperation. When the cases are falling apart because of lack of cooperation from the states, you hear about “incompetence,” but the reality is that there is simply no police force to accomplish these tasks”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale            &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Kenyan government has given “no cooperation whatsoever” in the ICC investigation and has “created a climate of fear” in those in Kenya who attempt to.&lt;br /&gt;
— Michael Greco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diasporamessenger.com/us-groups-to-debate-kenyan-icc-cases/&quot;&gt;Press Release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bangladesh War Crimes Tribunal</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/25/bangladesh-war-crimes-tribunal/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/25/bangladesh-war-crimes-tribunal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 25, the ABA held a discussion on the Bangladesh War Crimes Tribunal at Georgetown University Law Center. The purpose of the discussion was to address the shortcomings of the Tribunal and to present some of its accomplishments. For instance, moderator Michael Greco, former ABA president and chair of the ABA-ICC Project, pointed out that the mandate of this course came on the heels of the Bangladesh Atrocities, beginning back in the 1970s; this type of legislation was a rarity at that time, predating all modern international criminal tribunals by decades. Criticisms of the Bangladesh Tribunal stem primarily from the procedures being employed by the Tribunal, which give the appearance of impropriety. As former Defense Team Attorney Toby Cadman suggested in quoting Justice Jackson, “If you are determined to execute a man in any event, there is no occasion to hold a trial.” Full video of the panel can be found below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I completely agree that I dont think it matters how long we wait, there should be a system. Whether its five years or forty years, I think that the fact that forty three years has passed is not a reason not to establish a process.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Toby Cadman                                                                                                                                                                                 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you are determined to execute a man in any event, there is no occasion for a trial”&lt;br /&gt;
— Justice Jackson as quoted by Toby Cadman                                                                                                                                                              &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The legislation prohibits any challenge to the legislation itself, to the jurisdiction of the tribunal, and to the appointment of any particular judge. Taking an extreme example, we are prevented from challenging and seeking the removal of a judge on any ground.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Toby Cadman     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The International Criminal Justice Movement: Past, Present, Future - and Where the U.S. Fits into It All</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/20/the-international-criminal-justice-movement-past-present-future/"/>
   <updated>2014-02-20T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2014/02/20/the-international-criminal-justice-movement-past-present-future</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 20, 2014, the University of Denver Sturm College of Law welcomed Kip Hale, director of the ABA-ICC Project, to give a talk at an event hosted by the College of Law’s International Law Society and the Ved Nanda Center for International and Comparative Law. In his talk on international criminal justice and the US role in the field, Kip Hale explained the undesirable consequences caused by the United States and other states not fully engaging with the ICC, and detailed adverse effects of obsolete anti-ICC legislations passed by US Congress in the early 2000’s. In discussing the ICC’s first twelve years of operations, Hale stated, “a prevalent issue that has come out of the international criminal court system is international cooperation and assistance. The Court does not have police forces to do these things; cooperation is essential.” Hale concluded by stating there was reason to be positive about the future of US-ICC relations. Despite past and current difficulties, U.S.-ICC relations are “not broken, but it needs to be worked on.” The full talk is available by clicking the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When Churchill and Stalin were discussing who to summarily execute, it was FDR who stepped in to say that there would be no executions without due process of law. The United States has always been involved with these ideals.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A prevalent issue that has come out of the international criminal court system is international cooperation and assistance. The Courts don’t have police forces to do these things; cooperation is essential.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There are two main issues as I see it right now, the first is complementarity; this 	issue is incredibly important for the international community to figure out. The second is the relationship between the ICC and the states; it is not broken but it needs to be worked on.” &lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://du-denverlaw.hosted.panopto.com/Panopto/Pages/Viewer.aspx?id=d2b0a003-647c-49f4-a270-340bacb39fb7&quot;&gt;Video and Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://owa.abanet.org/exchange/weiglk/Inbox/Just%20resending%20so%20all%20in%20one%20place..EML/FW:%20Also.EML/aba_du_speech.jpg/C58EA28C-18C0-4a97-9AF2-036E93DDAFB3/aba_du_speech.jpg?attach=1&quot;&gt;Flyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>United Nations War Crimes Commission Event</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/08/07/united-nations-war-crimes-commission-event/"/>
   <updated>2013-08-07T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/08/07/united-nations-war-crimes-commission-event</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On August 7, 2013, American Univeristy Washington College of Law hosted a panel of experts to discuss the utility, history, and impact of the United Nations War Crimes Commission (1943-48). The panelists discussed the exclusion of the public from the Commission’s archives, and the potential utility of publicizing the archives. Kip Hale, director of the ABA-ICC Project who has previously litigated at international criminal tribunals, explained that the the archives would be useful in providing guidance for present and future international criminal trials. Kip stated that guidance would be helpful, and potentially necessary, because “we are never going to get rid of atrocities its just about how we deal with them in the aftermath.” Click the link below to hear the full discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We have the international community coming together and saying, ‘This is what we want to bind ourselves to going forward.’”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The U.N. War Crimes Commission Archives shifts a paradigm from where we always talk about Nuremburg and tells us there’s actually more information out there, and we can say which are the legal concepts that were criminal at that time, or these are the perpetrators that we can hold accountable”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’re never going to get rid of atrocities, its just about how to deal with them in the aftermath.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wcl.american.edu/podcast/audio/20130305_WCL_WCRO.mp3&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://owa.abanet.org/exchange/weiglk/Inbox/Just%20resending%20so%20all%20in%20one%20place..EML/FW:%20Audio%20from%20the%20War%20Crimes%20Commission%20Event-1.EML/photo.JPG/C58EA28C-18C0-4a97-9AF2-036E93DDAFB3/photo.JPG?attach=1;&quot;&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://owa.abanet.org/exchange/weiglk/Inbox/Just%20resending%20so%20all%20in%20one%20place..EML/FW:%20Audio%20from%20the%20War%20Crimes%20Commission%20Event-1.EML/photo2.JPG/C58EA28C-18C0-4a97-9AF2-036E93DDAFB3/photo2.JPG?attach=1;&quot;&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://owa.abanet.org/exchange/weiglk/Inbox/Just%20resending%20so%20all%20in%20one%20place..EML/FW:%20Audio%20from%20the%20War%20Crimes%20Commission%20Event-1.EML/photo3%20cropped.jpg/C58EA28C-18C0-4a97-9AF2-036E93DDAFB3/photo3%20cropped.jpg?attach=1&quot;&gt;Photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Is It So Hard To Convict War Criminals?</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/06/20/why-is-it-so-hard-to-convict-war-criminals/"/>
   <updated>2013-06-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/06/20/why-is-it-so-hard-to-convict-war-criminals</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 20, 2013 Huffington Post Live hosted an interview of experts in the field of international criminal justice. The panel addressed the difficulties faced by the ICC and other international criminal justice endeavors in obtaining convictions of alleged atrocity criminals. The trouble with witnesses protection and  available resources to the Court was stressed by panel members, along with the difficulty the Prosecutor faces in obtaining evidence in on-going conflicts or post-conflict situations. Nonetheless, each expert ultimately remained optimistic that the Court, while young, was on the right track. As explained by the director of the ABA-ICC Project, Kip Hale, “By all objective measures we are doing far better, and in a better position, in prosecuting and holding people accountable for the core crimes: war crimes, genocide, and crimes against humanity. A mere 25 years it would have been laughed at for someone to say that a government leader should be held accountable.” On the panel as well were James Goldston, Executive Director, Open Society Justice Initiative; Prof. David Kaye, UC Irvine School of Law; and James Jackson, Defense Lawyer, International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia.                      &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“By all objective measures we are doing far better, and are in a better position, in 	prosecuting people and holding people accountable for the core crimes; war crimes, genocide, and crimes against humanity. A mere 25 years ago it would have been laughed at for someone to say that a government leader should be held accountable.”  &lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What is required here is solid investigations solid prosecutions but also political and financial will. In the case of Kenyata, now the president of his country, it is an enormous challenge to undertake a case under those circumstances, where he has such control over many means at his disposal; and that is true in other situations as well.”&lt;br /&gt;
— James Goldston&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>International Corporate Liability in Conflict Zones</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/03/21/international-corporate-liability-in-conflict-zones/"/>
   <updated>2013-03-21T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2013/03/21/international-corporate-liability-in-conflict-zones</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The full day, international conference in Paris, France, on March 21, 2013 brought together experts in the field of corporate liability in conflict zones. After the conference, Madam Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, Fatou Bensouda (The Gambia) sat down for an interview and explained that alleged ignorance is no defense when it comes to corporate liability. She called for a more proactive approach by corporations stating that, “I think that private companies can actually do a lot to ensure that the access that those in the conflict have to weapons, to money, to the illegal trade, is not enhanced. At least,” she went on, “they can start by doing that.” Madam Prosecutor stated that she would not at all be opposed to corporate liability being a future subject in the ICC, at least for those who directly contribute to these atrocities in conflict zones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I have seen the sort of horrors that are committed on the civilian community, a woman I talked to who had her 8 children’s throat slashed by units that was committed by Bosco Ntganda, the fact that he was able to remain free sent a signal to individuals in that Province that there was impunity. That made it very hard to do other things that we wanted to do there, to restore the rule of law.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Ambassador Rapp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think that private companies can actually do a lot to ensure that the access that those in the conflict have to weapons, to money, to the illegal trade, is not enhanced. At least they can start by doing that.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Madam Prosecutor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The International Criminal Court at 10</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2012/10/12/the-international-criminal-court-at-10/"/>
   <updated>2012-10-12T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2012/10/12/the-international-criminal-court-at-10</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November 11 and 12, 2012, the Whitney R. Harris World Law Institute at Washington University School of Law held an international conference commemorating the tenth anniversary of the International Criminal Court (ICC). The conference included a celebration of the memory of Nuremberg Tribunal prosecutor Whitney R. Harris and his 100th birthday, as well as a day of remembrance to honor the victims of atrocity crimes. One of the panels at this distinguished conference was on US-ICC relations, shown in full in the link below, and revolved around the developments and challenges of US engagement with the ICC, past, present and future. This panel included Elizabeth Andersen, executive director of the American Society of International Law; John Washburn, convenor of the American NGO Coalition for the ICC, Prof. Jordan Paust, University of Houston Law Center, and Kip Hale, director of the ABA-ICC Project. Several panelist commented on different aspects of the US’ inconsistent, yet burgeoning relationship with the ICC, including Kip Hale who pointed out that “we have to think about the U.S.-ICC relationship as larger than just the United States Government and the ICC.” The importance of United States cooperation with the ICC was commented on by several, and summarized by a video of Whitney R. Harris, in which he stated, “Civilization can no longer tolerate the commission of crimes against humanity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The ICC experience is a very important warning to the United States that if other countries care enough about a new international organization and what it is committed to do, they can do it without you. That is a very important lesson in this.”&lt;br /&gt;
— John Washburn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Not only do we not oppose the ICC’s investigation and prosecutions in Sudan, but we support its investigation and prosecution in these atrocities.”&lt;br /&gt;
— John Bellinger, as quoted by moderator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“After 12 years I think we have reset the default on the US relationship with the court from hostility to positive engagement. In this case, principled engagement works to protect our interests to improve the outcome and to bring us renewed international goodwill.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Harold Kowe, State Department Legal Advisor, quoted by moderator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think we have to think about the U.S. - ICC relationship as larger than the United States government and the ICC.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Kip Hale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you take the long view you are looking at the prevention of armed conflicts and atrocities that ultimately do involve American treasure and blood.”&lt;br /&gt;
— David Scheffer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The common sense of mankind demands that law shall not stop with the punishment of petty crimes by little people, it must also reach men of who possess themselves of great power and make deliberate and concerted use of it, to set in motion evils which leave no home in the world untouched.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Justice Jackson, quoted by Ambassador Rapp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Civilization can no longer tolerate the commission of crimes against humanity”&lt;br /&gt;
— Whitney R. Harris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We must never forget that the record on which we judge these defendants today is the record on which history will judge us tomorrow”&lt;br /&gt;
— Justice Jackson, quoted by Ambassador Rapp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The ICC needs the support of the US this great country which time and again had a decisive role in bringing about the fall of tyranny and re the rule of law. The Court needs American support morally politically materially and in other ways and it remains also my hope that one day the judges may have an American colleague on the bench.”&lt;br /&gt;
— His Excellency Judge Hans Peter-Kaul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- 
countries care enough about a new international organization and what it is 
committed to do, they can do it without you. That is a very important lesson in this.”
 --&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introduction & The ICC as a New Judicial Institution: Achievements and Challenges ICC Turns Ten: Reviewing the Past, Assessing the Future</title>
   <link href="http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2012/05/11/introduction-and-the-icc-as-a-new-judicial-institution/"/>
   <updated>2012-05-11T12:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.aba-icc.org/aba-news/event/2012/05/11/introduction-and-the-icc-as-a-new-judicial-institution</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On May 11, 2012, experts from across the globe gathered at Stanford University Law School for the first conference to be held in the United States commemorating the ICC’s first ten years of operations. Over several panels, various experts discussed the progress achieved and present obstacles facing the ICC at ten years old. Although many experts agreed that the ICC has overcome many challenges there still remains a great deal of work to be done. Former Nuremberg Prosecutor Ben Ferencz concluded his remarks by saying, “[w]hat you’ve got to do now is work on improving the Court. It will come along. It is a prototype with all of the difficulties.” One such group in the United States working to support the ICC is the American Bar Association. Introducing the ABA’s recently founded effort that works closely with international organizational partners, former ABA President and chair of the ABA-ICC Project, Michael Greco, stated, “The International Criminal Court Project of the ABA will say to those in the United States who may fear or doubt the ICC, that the American legal profession believes in the ICC, that the imminent bipartisan members of the ICC Project Board of Advisers believe in the ICC, that support for the ICC not only serves the interest of the United States but safeguards the values that we as a civilized people have longed cherished, that we are comfortable with the Court and its important role in the world, that everyone in America should be comfortable with the Court.” The full conference can be viewed below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“War is a terrible thing. It is not something that is glorious. It is not the path to power. It is not the path to privilege or conquest or being a great thing. It is awful. That point of view is not something that is unique to me, because I can quote General Eisenhower who, when he was President of the United States said that, ‘the time has come for us to recognize that we have to give up force and rely only on the rule of law.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Ben Ferencz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What you’ve got to do now is work on improving the Court. It will come along. It is a prototype, with all the difficulties. When the Wright Brothers were peddling and they thought they couldn’t make it fly, well, we all flew in here today.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Ben Ferencz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We have obligations under international humanitarian law, to investigate these kinds of activities, not to engage in unlawful killings of civilians, not to engage in indiscriminate attacks,and to investigate them when they occur. If our forces are violating these rules, in my view, the US is best served by carrying out genuine investigations of them.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Alan Wiener                                                                                                                                                                  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The words, indeed the imperative of ‘never again’ must not merely be set to paper and left to politics, but must be institutionalized under a just rule of law.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Michael Greco &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Of one thing we may be sure, the future will never have to ask, with misgiving, what could the Nazis have said in their favor? History will know that whatever could be said, they were allowed to say. they have been given the kind of trial which they in the day of their pomp and power, never gave to any man.”&lt;br /&gt;
— Justice Jackson, quoted by Michael Greco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
